export const chapter = "Chapter - 2: Beginning of Colonial Power";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Who was the first European to open the sea route from Europe to India via the Cape of Good Hope in 1498?",
        optionA: "Christopher Columbus",
        optionB: "Vasco da Gama",
        optionC: "Ferdinand Magellan",
        correctAnswer: "B) Vasco da Gama",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which European nation initially enjoyed a monopoly of trade with India during the 16th century?",
        optionA: "Spanish",
        optionB: "Portuguese",
        optionC: "Dutch",
        correctAnswer: "B) Portuguese",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What were some of the popular Indian commodities in Europe during the medieval period?",
        optionA: "Gold and diamonds",
        optionB: "Cotton, silk, and spices",
        optionC: "Tea and coffee",
        correctAnswer: "B) Cotton, silk, and spices",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What brought European traders into conflict with each other when trading with India?",
        optionA: "Competition over controlling coastal territories",
        optionB: "Religious differences",
        optionC: "Lack of interest in Indian goods",
        correctAnswer: "A) Competition over controlling coastal territories",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who was the British officer who played a crucial role in the Battle of Plassey in 1757?",
        optionA: "Robert Clive",
        optionB: "Vasco da Gama",
        optionC: "Christopher Columbus",
        correctAnswer: "A) Robert Clive",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In which battle was Mir Jafar a traitor, leading to a significant British victory in India?",
        optionA: "Battle of Buxar",
        optionB: "Battle of Plassey",
        optionC: "Battle of Palashi",
        correctAnswer: "B) Battle of Plassey",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What marked the beginning of direct British interference in India according to the text?",
        optionA: "The Battle of Buxar",
        optionB: "The establishment of the British East India Company",
        optionC: "The Battle of Plassey",
        correctAnswer: "C) The Battle of Plassey",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which Mughal emperor had to grant Diwani rights of Bengal, Bihar, and Orissa to the British East India Company?",
        optionA: "Akbar",
        optionB: "Shah Jahan",
        optionC: "Shah Alam II",
        correctAnswer: "C) Shah Alam II",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What system was brought to an end in 1772 by Warren Hastings, the Governor of Bengal?",
        optionA: "Dual administration",
        optionB: "Monopoly trading",
        optionC: "Colonial rule",
        correctAnswer: "A) Dual administration",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who became the first Governor General of India in 1774, solidifying British imperialistic ambitions in India?",
        optionA: "Siraj-ud-daulah",
        optionB: "Mir Qasim",
        optionC: "Warren Hastings",
        correctAnswer: "C) Warren Hastings",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Vasco da Gama opened the sea route from Europe to India via the Cape of Good Hope in ______.",
        optionA: "1492",
        optionB: "1498",
        optionC: "1502",
        correctAnswer: "1498",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In the medieval period, Indian and Arab traders enjoyed a monopoly over trade, carrying merchandise from India to far-off places in Asia and Europe via treacherous overland routes. They earned handsomely, especially from commodities like cotton, silk, and ______.",
        optionA: "Diamonds",
        optionB: "Spices",
        optionC: "Tea",
        correctAnswer: "Spices",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Portuguese were the first European traders to come to India and enjoyed a ______ of trade throughout the sixteenth century.",
        optionA: "Monopoly",
        optionB: "Partnership",
        optionC: "Cartel",
        correctAnswer: "Monopoly",
      },
      {
        question:
          "European traders, including the Dutch, French, and British, came to India due to the lucrative trade opportunities, which led to increased ______ and competition among them.",
        optionA: "Collaboration",
        optionB: "Prices",
        optionC: "Conflicts",
        correctAnswer: "Conflicts",
      },
      {
        question:
          "European traders settled in coastal areas of India, as they depended on ______ routes for trade.",
        optionA: "Overland",
        optionB: "River",
        optionC: "Sea",
        correctAnswer: "Sea",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Battle of Plassey in 1757 marked the beginning of direct British interference in India, as Robert Clive led a small British army to victory, and Siraj-ud-daulah was captured and put to ______.",
        optionA: "Work",
        optionB: "Trial",
        optionC: "Death",
        correctAnswer: "Death",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The British East India Company obtained Diwani rights from Shah Alam II, granting them the power to collect taxes in the provinces of Bengal, Bihar, and ______.",
        optionA: "Madras",
        optionB: "Orissa",
        optionC: "Punjab",
        correctAnswer: "Orissa",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The British introduced the system of dual administration, where they had Diwani rights, but law and order, criminal justice, and protection of territories were the responsibilities of the ______.",
        optionA: "Local rulers",
        optionB: "Mughal Empire",
        optionC: "Nawab",
        correctAnswer: "Nawab",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Economic exploitation by the British East India Company resulted in a financial crisis in Bengal, and a famine in 1770 claimed nearly one-third of the population due to heavy taxation without any ______.",
        optionA: "Consequences",
        optionB: "Benefits",
        optionC: "Responsibilities",
        correctAnswer: "Benefits",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Warren Hastings, the Governor of Bengal, ended the system of dual administration in 1772, bringing Bengal under the direct control of the British East India Company. Calcutta was made the ______.",
        optionA: "Trading hub",
        optionB: "Capital",
        optionC: "Fortified city",
        correctAnswer: "Capital",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Apartments, flats, and bungalows have all modern facilities.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Houses in olden times were made up of mud, bricks, wood, stone chips, etc.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In olden times, all family members sat together in the evening in the verandah.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "Shelter is not a basic need for everyone.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "People who live in slums lead a miserable life.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "Dharavi in Mumbai is the first largest slum in Asia.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
